Guide to the New York State College of Agriculture Dept. of Vegetable Crops records, 1920-1940.
New York State College of Agriculture Dept. of Vegetable Crops records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Agriculture Dept. of Vegetable Crops records, 1920-1940.
21-35-1582
New York State College of Agriculture. Department of Vegetable Crops.
4.9 cubic feet.
Survey, research data, publications, maps, and subject files
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Survey and research data, subject files, and other records deriving from the Department, and pertaining to vegetable science and industry in New York State.
Also, four Vegetable Crops/Fruit and Vegetable Science/Horticulture department seminar books, 1961-1972, 1972-1984, 1984-1995; 1996-2003, with listing of weekly seminars, presentations by graduate students, faculty and visitors, and signatures of attendees.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
In 1992, a Department of Fruit and Vegetable Science was established, combining the Departments of Vegetable Science and Pomology. On July 1, 2000, the Department of Horticulture was established, combining the Department of Fruit and Vegetable Science with the Department of Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Survey and research data, subject files, and other records deriving from the Department, and pertaining to vegetable science and industry in New York State.
Also, four Vegetable Crops/Fruit and Vegetable Science/Horticulture department seminar books, 1961-1972, 1972-1984, 1984-1995; 1996-2003, with listing of weekly seminars, presentations by graduate students, faculty and visitors, and signatures of attendees.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture.
Subjects:
Agriculture -- New York (State); Vegetables -- Study and teaching; Vegetable trade -- New York (State); Fruit -- Study and teaching.; Victory gardens.; Agriculture; Vegetable trade; Victory gardens
Places:
New York (State)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Land utilization survey, 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Notebooks and data
  Chemung county
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Data by farm, records 1-30
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Data by farm, records 31-57
- Land utilization survey, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 4-12)
  Data by farm, records mixed
  Steuben county
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Notebooks, data and soil survey maps of Columbia county
  Columbia county
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Data by farm, records 1-23
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Data by farm, records 24-50
- Land utilization survey, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Notebook
  Erie county
- Land utilization survey, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Notebook and data sheets with Monroe County material
  Monroe county
  Orleans county
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Notebook and data
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Data by farm, records 1-24
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Data by farm, records 25-50
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Data by farm, records 51-79
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Data by farm, records 80-100
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Data by farm, records 101-124
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Data by farm, records 125-151
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Data by farm, records 152-179
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Data by farm, records 180-200
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Data by farm, records 201-225
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Data by farm, records 226-269
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Data by farm, records 270-299
- Land utilization survey, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Data by farm, records 300-339
- Land utilization survey, 1930-1933 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Notebook, survey records
  Long Island
- Land utilization survey, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Maps, tour programs
- Land utilization survey, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Survey records, data by farm
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Data by farm, records 260-313 and maps
  Nassau county
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Data by farm, records 1-21
  Suffolk county
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Data by farm, records 45-79
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Data by farm, records 81-179
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Data by farm, records 77-100
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Data by farm, records 101-125
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Data by farm, records 126-150
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Data by farm, records 151-180
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Data by farm, records 181-198
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Data by farm, records 201-229
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Data by farm, records 230-251
- Land utilization survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  Data cards by farm
- Land utilization survey, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Drafts, correspondence and notes
- Land utilization survey, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Soil type summary and correspondence
- Long Island Study, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Report of land utilization survey, second copy, 1st carbon
- Land utilization survey, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Weather data
  Genesee county
- Land utilization survey, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  County weather data
- Soil and crop survey, 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Soil, crop and grower information, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Soil and crop records, 1932-1935 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Soil and crop records, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Muck land survey, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Growing areas and crop data
- Muck land survey, 1925-1928 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Reports and data
- Muck land survey, 1931-1936 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Reports and information
- Land utilization survey, 1930-1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Canning crops records. Arranged by canning company and grower.
- Land utilization survey, 1932-1935 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Canning crops records
- Land utilization survey, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Canning crops schools, 1934-1946 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Programs and notes
- Potato conference, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Vegetable schools for growers and extension agents, 1934-1939 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Programs, notes and papers
- Vegetable schools for growers and extension agents, 1940-1945 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Winter vegetable meetings, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, programs and papers
- Winter vegetable meetings, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Winter vegetable meetings, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Schedules for meetings, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Miscellaneous extension correspondence and programs
- Farm and home week, 1936-1943 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Programs, correspondence and papers
- Correspondence, 1933-1940 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  General extension questions and problems
  Delaware county
- Correspondence, 1932-1944 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1934-1939 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1933-1946 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Niagara county
- Soils and vegetable crops management, papers by W.C. Barnes, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Land utilization, Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Miscellaneous correspondence
- Greenhouse cucumbers, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Contains 1905 letter to Professor John Craig from Dr. Jabez Fisher of Fitchburg, Massachusetts. Generally credited as the pioneer of cucumber forcing in New England; describes late 1800's experiments
- Cabbage correspondence, 1901-1902 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Correspondence with primarily Genesee County cabbage growers to assess problems
- Lettuce tests, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Correspondence
- Vegetable variety trials, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  Includes seed companies correspondence
- Cauliflower research, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  Research results
- Field experiments, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Results and correspondence
- Field experiments, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Results, correspondence and includes some greenhouse experiments
- Liming of vegetable crops, 1930-1939 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Correspondence and literature
- Boron and vegetable crops, 1930-1940 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Soil testing kits, 1934-1939 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Seed requests, 1940-1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Correspondence with seed companies
- Seed certification, 1940-1945 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Correspondence with the New York Seed Improvement Co-operative Association, Inc.
- Paul Work course references, 1928-1935 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- USDA agricultural conservation program, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Farmers' Institute for State Institution Farm Workers, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Sponsored by NYS Department of Agriculture and Markets. Contains program and correspondence
- Cortland county conference committee, 1936-1943 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Cortland county
- Cabbage campaign, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  "Grow Better Cabbage" campaign of 1935, newsletters, articles
- Subsistence gardens, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Notes, correspondence and programs
- Victory gardens, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Correspondence, literature, programs and articles
- Victory gardens, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Iron age, farm machinery (for vegetables), 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Correspondence with the Iron Age division of A.B. Farquhar Co., Ltd., York, Pennsylvania
- Publications from the National Association of Manufacturers, New York City, 1936-1940 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Bulletin of the Committee on Agricultural Cooperation no.9-12, (1936), Special Bulletin December 1938 and July 1940, Report December 1938, Special Study no.2-4 (1937) and December 1938, Special Supplementary Study 1937-1938, Special Report 1938-1939
- N.Y.A. Student Work Program, 1939-1943 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Correspondence with Cornell University Placement Bureau to find summer workers through this program
- New York State Agricultural Goals Conference, 1943-10-14-1943-10-16 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Held at Onondaga Hotel, Syracuse, New York. Programs and notes.
- Attendance lists, 1961-03-23-1972-11-02 (Box 4)
  Department seminars in the Department of Vegetable Crops
- Attendance lists, 1972-11-16-1984-09-20 (Box 4)
- Attendance lists, 1984-09-27-1995-12-07 (Box 4)
- Attendance lists, 1996-01-17-2003-12-11 (Box 4)
  Department seminars in the Department of Horticulture
- Topographical map, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Topographical map, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Topographical map, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  South Livingston county
- Topographical map, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Ontario county
- Topographical map, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Chautauqua county
- Topographical map, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Topographical map, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Topographical map, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Bergen area